Moving on in our brief,
摘要的第二部分
we're going to our customer story.
就是客户故事
This is where we really start to break open the segment that we've selected.
我们会在客户故事部分 深入讨论之前选择的目标群体
For this example, we're going to target sports enthusiasts who shop at our grocery store,
比如在超市例子里 我们的目标群体是运动人士
because we want them to buy more snacks.
我们希望他们可以购买更多的饮料
For this, you're going to need to answer a series of questions.
要达成这个目标 首先你要回答一些问题
The first one I want you to think about is,
第一个
where is this targets attention?
目标群体平时都关注些什么？
For our sports enthusiast,
对于运动人士来说
perhaps they're listening to sports talk radio,
他们可能喜欢听运动电台
spending time watching ESPN.
看 CCTV-5 体育频道
Maybe they're frequent sports bars.
运动主题酒吧
It's also very likely that they buy their teams a peril.
他们也可能买球队的周边 例如队服
They may also be using their phone or the web to look up sports stats.
或者用手机或者网络查看赛季数据
They may even have an app that gives them up to date details,
甚至下载了应用 来随时查看关于比赛的
about the game they're watching.
最新的消息
From here, we need to evaluate where is our effort.
解决好了第一个问题 我们再来看应该在哪里花费精力和时间
Let's say right now the grocery store is only sending out a circular.
假设 目前超市的唯一市场营销手段就是传单
It's one ad that goes out every Sunday to everybody in our target market,
每周六给距离超市 20 里内的所有住户发一份传单
We now need to ask ourselves,
那么问题来了
how effective is this effort?
这个传单会有效果吗？
It's really clearly not effective for this goal.
对于我们想要实现的目标 这个方式显然不合理
It's not going to meet the needs of the customer segment.
它不符合我们的目标群体的需求
So from here, we really need to then evaluate where should we focus our changes.
接下来 我们就要评估应该在哪些方面做出改变
In this case, we need to be launching marketing efforts in
在这个例子里 我们需要在能触达到这些运动人士的渠道里
the channels that will be capturing the attention of our sports enthusiast.
开展营销活动
Anywhere that they're spending time,
他们的时间和精力花在哪里
we might evaluate making sure our brand is present.
我们的品牌就要如影随形
We also need to incentivize our high margin items.
同时 我们需要曝光这些高利润的产品
When you walk into the store,
当客户走进超市时
it needs to be evident that we're pushing these products.
他们需要看到这些是我们主推的产品
We could do this by discounting or where we place the products in the store.
我们可以做促销打折或者摆在明显的地方
We also likely need to find a way to connect the sports theme to these snacks,
同时 我们也可以用某种方式 让这些产品与运动主题关联性更高
and that can be done using displays,
比如 用海报来展示我们支持的队
or by indicating these types of connections in the display or TV ads that we're running.
在投放的电视广告或者海报里彰显这些关联
It's really important that our brand looks like it aligns with these sports fans.
总之 要让品牌与目标人群契合 这很重要
Now we need to start considering,
好了 现在要考虑
what should we be doing now and later.
现在以及未来需要做什么
Well, we know that we need to align our messaging.
我们肯定需要保证信息的一致性
We know that we really need to be attractive to this audience.
我们需要提高对目标人群的吸引力
From here, we're really going to be looking at
所以 我们会关注潜在的客户旅程
the prospective customer journey and applying it to a map.
并将其可视化
We're going to do this so we can evaluate further and with more detail,
这样 我们就能更深入、更详细地评估
what we need to be measuring to further influence the decisions that we make,
有哪些地方需要关注 来进一步确认决策
and to further measure what's happening as this customer moves through this journey.
以及更好地了解目标人群的典型客户在通过客户旅程时 是怎样的体验
Now, an easy way to do this,
一种简单的方式是
is to set up a grid.
建立表格
You can do this in Excel.
你可以新建一个 Excel 表格
List all of your channels is rows along the left side,
左边是所有的渠道 每一个渠道占一行
and then create the funnel labels as columns across the top.
然后 漏斗的五个阶段各为一列
Let's say our channels are as follows; WEB, DISPLAY,
假设我们有这些渠道： WEB 网站, DISPLAY 海报,
FACEBOOK, TELEVISION, RADIO, IN-STORE, PRINT and PHONE.
FACEBOOK, TELEVISION 电视, RADIO 电台, IN-STORE 实体店, PRINT 纸媒 and PHONE 手机
Of course, we have our funnel: AWARENESS,
漏斗的五个阶段是： AWARENESS 认知,
INTEREST, DESIRE, ACTION and ADVOCACY.
INTEREST 兴趣, DESIRE 渴望, ACTION 购买 and ADVOCACY 自发宣传
Now, we simply highlight the customer journey we are going to seek to influence.
接下来 我们要高亮可以帮助我们达成目标的客户旅程
Let's say this audience is watching TV,
比如 这个客户喜欢看电视
so we decide that we want to run a local commercial to drive awareness to our brand.
那么 我们决定投放一个电视广告 来提高品牌知名度
So we know that this customer is going to start at awareness with the television.
所以 这个客户的认知阶段是始于电视
From here, they're going to move into interest.
然后 要去到兴趣阶段
So how do we further capture and reinforce that?
我们怎样巩固这个客户对我们的认知以及进一步发展他的兴趣呢？
Perhaps we're going to send a direct mail campaign.
可以发送邮件
We're going to run radio spots covering the deals.
可以购买广播的插播时间 广播我们的促销活动
You might even offer a discount when you wear your game day t-shirt.
也可以做一个促销活动 只要他穿了比赛官方 T-恤 就可以享受折扣价
From here we're going to move them through desire and action,
这样 我们就使得客户一旦走进超市
and will likely do that once they're in store.
就会进入到渴望与购买阶段
We create that desire again by decorating the store,
重新装饰超市 也可以增强他们的渴望
moving those high margin products upfront,
或者把高利润产品挪到前排的货架
and making discounts really visible.
或者把促销活动做得特别显眼
Next, we have advocacy.
接下来 自发宣传
So we perhaps encourage loyalty cards,
比如 可以鼓励办会员卡
because we have emails and cell phone numbers attach those loyalty cards,
因为会员卡需要提供邮件和手机号码等信息
which allows us to send follow-up email messaging or text messages,
所以我们后续也可以在下一个赛季给这些客户
before the next big game.
发邮件或者短信促销
This is our reference funnel.
这是我们的参考漏斗
It is the ideal path that they will take.
也是目标群体的理想路径
It's going to be okay,
当然 如果他们是 Z 型路径
if they split off this path zig-zag,
或者半路跑掉
or if this path splits into multiple channels from time to time.
或者时不时就发展至多个渠道 也是可以的
Now, we look at this and we think deeply about what metrics we need to measure.
现在 我们再来看看这张表格 思考下我们需要衡量哪些指标
We look at TV, and from here we outline what do we need to measure here.
比如电视广告 我们来列举下需要关注的指标
How are we going to know that this TV campaign was successful?
我们如何才能知道电视广告是成功的呢？
Are we going to look at traffic to our website?
根据网站流量？
Are we going to look at traffic in our store?
还是超市的客流量？
What are we going to measure to understand that
我们需要通过衡量哪些指标才能判断
that TV campaign did what it set out to do?
电视广告达成了目标？
For direct mail, we might need to connect some dots.
对于邮件 我们可能需要综合考虑一些因素
It could be a little harder to measure.
稍微会有点难衡量
Perhaps, we've included a coupon or some other way that we can
或者 我们可以在邮件里放入一张优惠券或者其他方式
identify that direct mail piece influenced the behavior,
来帮助我们判断邮件真的促使了客户的购买行为
or we're simply looking at overall lift.
或者 我们也可以看整体销量是否有提升
We're not so concerned with each individual piece,
我们不需要去关注每一个客户
but rather we're okay looking at the top line.
而是关注营业收入 就可以了
One other way that we could evaluate direct mail,
另一个衡量邮件效果的方式是
is if we run these campaigns often.
做各种对比活动
If we did this campaign without direct mail
比如做一个促销活动 但是不发送邮件
or to a certain segment that did not receive direct mail,
或者发送给一个之前没有收到过邮件的客户群体
we can compare that data.
然后通过比较来判定效果
From here we move into the store.
在超市实体店方面
Now we need to measure how many people are coming into the store.
我们需要衡量客流量
How does that compare to our baselines?
对比基准线 表现如何？
Are there any game day shifts?
是否在比赛当天 有显著提升？
Are we seeing more traffic in response to the games?
比赛与客流量之间是否有正相关？
How many people are responding to these discounts, redeeming them?
有多少人回应了我们的促销活动 而使用了优惠券？
We might also look at how many people are coming in wearing those game day shirt.
我们也可以看看有多少人是穿着比赛T恤来超市的
This is data that you can collect simply by observation.
这些是可以靠观察得出的数据
From here, we can then look at that final step,
我们现在可以看下最后的步骤
the emails and the text that we're sending out.
也就是我们发送出的邮件和短信本身
What is the open rate on those emails?
邮件打开率是多少？
Then what is the response or engagement on the text messages?
短信回复率是多少？
Use the customer story as a map,
把客户故事当做是指南
to guide not only your thinking,
不仅指导你的思路
but to unlock the metrics that you want to capture at each step.
而且为你后续在每个步骤抓取哪些指标提供依据